<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"> <channel> <title></title> <description>Debezium is an open source distributed platform for change data capture. Start it up, point it at your databases, and your apps can start responding to all of the inserts, updates, and deletes that other apps commit to your databases. Debezium is durable and fast, so your apps can respond quickly and never miss an event, even when things go wrong.</description> <sy:updatePeriod>daily</sy:updatePeriod> <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency> <link>https://debezium.io</link> <atom:link href="https://debezium.io/blog.atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.1.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While we remain on track with the upcoming Debezium 2.6 release, we are continuously looking at improvements and fixes that are being made that ensures that older releases continue to provide the best possible experience. With that, the team is pleased to announce the first maintenance release of Debezium 2.5, &lt;strong&gt;Debezium 2.5.1.Final&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;#8217;s dive into what this release includes and what you should be aware of while upgrading&amp;#8230;&amp;#8203;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/30/debezium-2-5-1-final-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/30/debezium-2-5-1-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/30/debezium-2-5-1-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.6.0.Alpha1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;A new year, a new preview release, in true Debezium fashion. The team is pleased to announce the first installment of the Debezium 2.6 release stream, &lt;strong&gt;Debezium 2.6.0.Alpha1&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;#8217;s take a moment and dive into these new features, understand how to use these to improve your change data capture experience&amp;#8230;&amp;#8203;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/22/debezium-2.6-alpha1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/22/debezium-2.6-alpha1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/22/debezium-2.6-alpha1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium and TimescaleDB</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this article, we are going to present and demonstrate a new feature delivered in Debezium 2.4 - the integration with the TimescaleDB database.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/timescale/timescaledb&quot;&gt;TimescaleDB&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source database designed to make SQL scalable for time-series data. It is implemented as an extension for the PostgreSQL database. This fact leads us to re-use the standard &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/documentation/reference/stable/connectors/postgresql.html&quot;&gt;Debezium PostgreSQL connector&lt;/a&gt; and implement TimescaleDB support as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://cwiki.apache.org/confluence/display/KAFKA/KIP-66%3A+Single+Message+Transforms+for+Kafka+Connect&quot;&gt;single message transform (SMT)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/11/Debezium-and-TimescaleDB/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 10:11:11 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/11/Debezium-and-TimescaleDB/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2024/01/11/Debezium-and-TimescaleDB/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.0.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the winter chill settles in, and we transition to the festive holiday season, our dedicated team has been busy preparing a special gift for the Debezium community. I am excited to share the immediate release of Debezium 2.5.0.Final, just in time for the holiday celebrations. Get ready to unwrap this latest minor version, filled with holiday cheer and exciting new features!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a moment and review all the new features, changes, and improvements that are included in Debezium 2.5, which includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20and%20fixVersion%20%20in%20(2.5.0.Alpha1%2C%202.5.0.Alpha2%2C%202.5.0.Beta1%2C%202.5.0.Beta2%2C%202.5.0.CR1%2C%202.5.0.Final)&quot;&gt;181 issues&lt;/a&gt; resolved by 37 unique contributors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/21/debezium-2-5-final-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/21/debezium-2-5-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/21/debezium-2-5-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Streamlined Performance: Debezium JDBC connector batch support</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the realm of data streaming optimization, even subtle improvements can make a significant impact. This article focuses on one such refinement: the introduction of batch support in Debezium&amp;#8217;s JDBC connector. We&amp;#8217;ll guide you through the process of enabling batches and share the practical outcomes of our performance testing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/20/JDBC-sink-connector-batch-support/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 10:11:11 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/20/JDBC-sink-connector-batch-support/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/20/JDBC-sink-connector-batch-support/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.0.CR1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we are just one step away from the Debezium 2.5 final release, I am pleased to announce that Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.5.0.CR1&lt;/strong&gt; is now available. This release includes a number of improvements like AWS SQS sink for Debezium Server, INSERT/DELETE semantics for incremental snapshot watermarking, ReselectColumnsPostProcessor, uniform Oracle LOB behavior.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, this release includes a variety of bug fixes and several breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a closer look at all these changes and improvements included in Debezium 2.5.0.CR1; as always, you can find the complete list of changes for this release in the &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.5/release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;. Please remember to take special note to any breaking changes that could affect your upgrade path.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/14/debezium-2-5-cr1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/14/debezium-2-5-cr1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/14/debezium-2-5-cr1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.0.Beta1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we begin to approach the final stretch for Debezium 2.5, I am pleased to announce that Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.5.0.Beta1&lt;/strong&gt; is now available. This release includes a number of improvements like support for MariaDB GTID, partitioning for Debezium Server EventHub&amp;#8217;s sink, native RabbitMQ streams Debezium Server sink, streaming from PostgreSQL 16 stand-by databases, MySQL high-precision source timestamps, field inclusion/exclusion with JDBC sink, some additional notifications for initial snapshots, and service account support for Debezium Operator CRDs. Additionally, this release includes a variety of bug fixes and several breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a closer look at all these changes and improvements included in Debezium 2.5.0.Beta1; as always, you can find the complete list of changes for this release in the &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.5/release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;. Please remember to take special note to any breaking changes that could affect your upgrade path.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/04/debezium-2-5-beta1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/04/debezium-2-5-beta1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/12/04/debezium-2-5-beta1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.1.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the year starts to come to a close, I am happy to announce the first maintenance release for the Debezium 2.4 release series, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.4.1.Final&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While our maintenance releases focus primarily on bug fixes and stability improvements, there are a few new features we back ported from our most recent Debezium 2.5 development series. All these new features focus on the Debezium Operator for Kubernetes, so lets take a quick deep dive into those details. As always, you can find the complete list of changes for this release in the &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.4/release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/16/debezium-2-4-1-final-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/16/debezium-2-4-1-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/16/debezium-2-4-1-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.0.Alpha2 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While it has only been two short weeks since our first preview release for the Debezium 2.5 release stream, I am happy to announce the immediate availability of the next preview release, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.5.0.Alpha2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release includes a variety of improvements, batch support for the JDBC Sink connector, seamless support for MongoDB documents that exceed the 16MB barrier, MySQL 8.2 compatibility, and signal improvements for SQL Server. Additionally, this release includes a variety of bug fixes and several breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a closer look at these changes and improvements that are included in Debezium 2.5.0.Alpha2; as always, you can find the complete list of changes for this release in the &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.5/release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;. Please remember to take special note to any breaking changes that could affect your upgrade path.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/10/debezium-2-5-alpha2-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/10/debezium-2-5-alpha2-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/11/10/debezium-2-5-alpha2-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.5.0.Alpha1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been about three weeks since we released Debezium 2.4, and in that time the team has been diligently working on what comes next in the evolution of Debezium. I am pleased to announce that today we have released Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.5.0.Alpha1&lt;/strong&gt;, the first preview release of Debezium&amp;#8217;s 2.5 release stream.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release includes many new exciting features as well as bug fixes, e.g. a brand-new IBM Informix connector, a preview support for MariaDB with the MySQL connector, improvements to the Debezium Server operator, Kafka 3.6.0 support, and much more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a closer look at these changes and features that are included in Debezium 2.5.0.Alpha1; as always, you can find the complete list of changes for this release in the &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.5/release-notes&quot;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt;. Please take special note of any breaking changes that could affect your upgrade path.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;ibm_informix_connector&quot;&gt;IBM Informix Connector&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Thanks to the contribution from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nrkljo&quot;&gt;Lars Johansson&lt;/a&gt;, Debezium 2.5 introduces a new connector to its portfolio to gather changes from IBM Informix. IBM Informix is an embeddable, high-performance database for integrating SQL, NoSQL, JSON, time-series, and spatial data in one place. It&amp;#8217;s designed for analytics at the edge, in the cloud, or on premise.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The IBM Informix connector is bundled just like any of our community lead connectors, it is available on Maven Central or you can download the plug-in archive from our &lt;a href=&quot;/releases/2.5&quot;&gt;Debezium 2.5&lt;/a&gt; releases page.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The maven artifact coordinates are:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;CodeRay highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code data-lang=&quot;xml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;io.debezium&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/groupId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;debezium-connector-informix&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/artifactId&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;2.5.0.Alpha1&lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/version&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;tag&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/dependency&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;If you would like contribute to the Informix connector, we have added a new repository under the Debezium organization, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/debezium/debezium-connector-informix&quot;&gt;debezium-connector-informix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d like to thank Lars Johansson for this contribution and his collaboration with the team, kudos!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;mariadb_preview_support&quot;&gt;MariaDB preview support&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The community has leveraged the MySQL connector as an alternative to capture changes from MariaDB for quite some time now; however that compatibility was primarily best-case effort.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium 2.5 release stream aims to bring MariaDB to the forefront as a first-class connector by taking a very clear and methodological approach to incrementally check, validate, and eventually support MariaDB at the same capacity that we do MySQL. Our goal and hope is that we can do this within the scope of the MySQL connector proper; however, there is still quite a bit of ongoing investigation around GTID support that may influence the path forward.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This first preview build of Debezium 2.5 has taken the first step, we&amp;#8217;ve verified that the code works against a single MariaDB database deployment, the test suite passes and we&amp;#8217;ve addressed any changes needed with the Binlog client to support that deployment. Our next steps is to look into GTID support, which MariaDB supports but using an approach that isn&amp;#8217;t compatible with MySQL.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for future builds as we continue to expand on this and we certainly welcome any early feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;oracle_streaming_metrics_changes&quot;&gt;Oracle Streaming Metrics Changes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In previous builds of Debezium, there was a single Oracle streaming metrics bean that exposed all metrics options that spanned across all three streaming adapters. This often lead to some confusion about what metrics are applicable to which streaming adapter so we wanted to define a clear distinction in this case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;With Debezium 2.5, the Oracle streaming metrics beans have been split into three different implementations, one for each adapter type. For observability stacks, this change should be completely transparent unless you were previously gathering a metric for one adapter type while using another. In this case you&amp;#8217;ll find that metric is no longer available.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Specifically for LogMiner users, several metrics have been renamed and the old metrics have been deprecated. While you will still be able to use the old metric names in Debezium 2.5, these are scheduled for removal in a future 2.7+ build. The metrics that were deprecated and renamed are as follows:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;table class=&quot;tableblock frame-all grid-all stretch table table-bordered table-striped&quot;&gt; &lt;colgroup&gt; &lt;col style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot;&gt; &lt;col style=&quot;width: 50%;&quot;&gt; &lt;/colgroup&gt; &lt;thead&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;th class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;Old/Deprecated Metric&lt;/th&gt; &lt;th class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;New Metric&lt;/th&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/thead&gt; &lt;tbody&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;CurrentRedoLogFileName&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;CurrentLogFileNames&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;RedoLogStatus&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;RedoLogStatuses&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;SwitchCounter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;LogSwitchCounter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;FetchingQueryCount&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;FetchQueryCount&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;HoursToKeepTransactionInBuffer&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;MillisecondsToKeepTransactionsInBuffer&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;TotalProcessingTimeInMilliseconds&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;TotalBatchProcessingTimeInMilliseconds&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;RegisteredDmlCount&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;TotalChangesCount&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;MillisecondsToSleepBetweenMiningQuery&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;SleepTimeInMilliseconds&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tbody&gt; &lt;tfoot&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;NetworkConnectionProblemsCounter&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;tableblock halign-left valign-top&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No replacement&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/tfoot&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;debezium_server_operator&quot;&gt;Debezium Server Operator&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium Server Operator for Kubernetes has been actively improved in this preview release of Debezium 2.5. Several improvements include:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ability to set image pull secrets in the CRDs &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6962&quot;&gt;DBZ-6962&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ability to set resource limits in the CRDs &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7052&quot;&gt;DBZ-7052&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Published OLM bundle scripts to Maven Central &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6995&quot;&gt;DBZ-6995&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support OKD/OpenShift catalog in OperatorHub release script &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7010&quot;&gt;DBZ-7010&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Display name and descriptions metadata available in OLM bundle &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7011&quot;&gt;DBZ-7011&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;New metrics endpoint for gathering metrics &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7053&quot;&gt;DBZ-7053&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As we continue to improve the Debezium Server Operator for Kubernetes, we&amp;#8217;d love to get your feedback.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;community_connectors&quot;&gt;Community connectors&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, there were several enhancements to our community led connectors for Google Spanner and Vitess, which include the following changes:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support for Cloud Spanner emulator with the Spanner connector &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6845&quot;&gt;DBZ-6845&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Resumable snapshot support for the Vitess connector &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7050&quot;&gt;DBZ-7050&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;other-changes&quot;&gt;Other fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition, there were quite a number of stability and bug fixes that made it into this release. These include the following:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Adding Debezium Server example using MySQL and GCP PubSub &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-4471&quot;&gt;DBZ-4471&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Refactor ElapsedTimeStrategy &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6778&quot;&gt;DBZ-6778&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Multiple debezium:offsets Redis clients &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6952&quot;&gt;DBZ-6952&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Wrong case-behavior for non-avro column name in sink connector &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6958&quot;&gt;DBZ-6958&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Handle properly bytea field for jdbc sink to postgresql &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6967&quot;&gt;DBZ-6967&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium jdbc sink process truncate event failure &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6970&quot;&gt;DBZ-6970&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Single quote replication includes escaped quotes for N(CHAR/VARCHAR) columns &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6975&quot;&gt;DBZ-6975&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Provide configuration option to exclude extension attributes from a CloudEvent &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6982&quot;&gt;DBZ-6982&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium jdbc sink should throw not supporting schema change topic exception &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6990&quot;&gt;DBZ-6990&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium doesn&amp;#8217;t compile with JDK 21 &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6992&quot;&gt;DBZ-6992&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;OLM bundle version for GA releases is invalid &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6994&quot;&gt;DBZ-6994&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further refactoring to correct downstream rendering of incremental snapshots topics &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6997&quot;&gt;DBZ-6997&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;ALTER TABLE fails when adding multiple columns to JDBC sink target &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6999&quot;&gt;DBZ-6999&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Invalid Link to zulip chat in CSV metadata &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7000&quot;&gt;DBZ-7000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Make sure to terminate the task once connectivity is lost to either the rebalance or sync topic &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7001&quot;&gt;DBZ-7001&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Missing .metadata.annotations.repository field in CSV metadata &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7003&quot;&gt;DBZ-7003&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Single quote replication and loss of data &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7006&quot;&gt;DBZ-7006&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remove deprecated embedded engine code &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7013&quot;&gt;DBZ-7013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Enable replication slot advance check &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7015&quot;&gt;DBZ-7015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add configuration option to CloudEventsConverter to retrieve id and type from headers &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7016&quot;&gt;DBZ-7016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle connector: Payload size over 76020 bytes are getting truncated &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7018&quot;&gt;DBZ-7018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Use optional schema for Timezone Converter tests &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7020&quot;&gt;DBZ-7020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;DDL statement couldn&amp;#8217;t be parsed &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7030&quot;&gt;DBZ-7030&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Blocking ad-hoc snapshot is not really blocking for MySQL &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7035&quot;&gt;DBZ-7035&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Fake ROTATE event on connection restart cleans metadata &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7037&quot;&gt;DBZ-7037&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Consolidate resource labels and annotations &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-7064&quot;&gt;DBZ-7064&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Altogether, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%202.5.0.Alpha1%20ORDER%20BY%20component%20ASC&quot;&gt;XX issues&lt;/a&gt; were fixed for this release. A big thank you to all the contributors from the community who worked on this release: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ani-sha&quot;&gt;Anisha Mohanty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bpaquet&quot;&gt;Bertrand Paquet&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/roldanbob&quot;&gt;Bob Roldan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Naros&quot;&gt;Chris Cranford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vidourem&quot;&gt;David Remy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dtseiler&quot;&gt;Don Seiler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gunnarmorling&quot;&gt;Gunnar Morling&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/harveyyue&quot;&gt;Harvey Yue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jcechace&quot;&gt;Jakub Cechacek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/novotnyJiri&quot;&gt;Jiri Novotny&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jpechane&quot;&gt;Jiri Pechanec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mfvitale&quot;&gt;Mario Fiore Vitale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/MarkDucommun&quot;&gt;Mark Ducommun&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nancyxu123&quot;&gt;Nancy Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/obabec&quot;&gt;Ondrej Babec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/prburgu&quot;&gt;Praveen Burgu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rajdangwal&quot;&gt;Rajendra Dangwal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rk3rn3r&quot;&gt;René Kerner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/roldanbob&quot;&gt;Robert Roldan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rkudryashov&quot;&gt;Roman Kudryashov&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eizners&quot;&gt;Sergey Eizner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ShuranZhang&quot;&gt;Shuran Zhang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twthorn&quot;&gt;Thomas Thornton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vjuranek&quot;&gt;Vojtech Juranek&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sean-k1&quot;&gt;sean&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s next?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;With the holiday season quickly approaching for many of us, you can expect that the release cadence for Debezium 2.5 to be shorter than usual. We intend to release often like always, but expect that we will likely only do one more alpha build before we began to transition into beta and release candidate builds. Our goal is to deliver Debezium 2.5.0.Final by mid-December, just in time for the holiday break.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While this condensed timeline doesn&amp;#8217;t give us lots of room, we have a lot still planned to include for Debezium 2.5. There is still lots of work to do on the MariaDB preview front, supporting GTID and multiple topology deployments. We&amp;#8217;re also working on improving the parallelization experience with Debezium Engine, batch support for the JDBC sink connector, MongoDB improvements around large BSON documents, and much more. You can find all the details for our continued plans for Debezium 2.5 on our &lt;a href=&quot;/roadmap&quot;&gt;roadmap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Lastly, I&amp;#8217;d like to remind everyone about the Debezium community meeting. I will be distributing details about the next meeting in the coming weeks, and I would urge folks to be on the look-out and try and stop by our virtual event in early December. It&amp;#8217;s a great way to meet the engineers working on Debezium, ask questions in an AMA style format, and to get insights not only into what all is part of Debezium 2.5, but also what lies ahead with Debezium 2.6 and 2.7 for early next year!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As always, please be sure to get in touch with us on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/debezium&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.zulipchat.com/login/#narrow/stream/302529-users&quot;&gt;Zulip chat&lt;/a&gt; if you have questions or feedback. Until next time, stay warm out there!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/26/debezium-2-5-alpha1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/26/debezium-2-5-alpha1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/26/debezium-2-5-alpha1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium Operator Takes off to the Clouds</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;With Debezium 2.3, we introduced a preview of a brand new Debezium Operator with the aim to provide seamless deployment of Debezium Server to Kubernetes (k8s) clusters. The Debezium 2.4.0.Final release brings the next step towards the full support of this component. With this release, we are happy to announce that Debezium Operator is now available in the OperatorHub &lt;a href=&quot;https://operatorhub.io/operator/debezium-operator&quot;&gt;catalog&lt;/a&gt; for Kubernetes as well as in the community operator catalog embedded in the OpenShift and OKD distributions. The operator remains in the incubation phase; however, the full support of this component is approaching fast.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/19/Debezium-Operator-Takes-off-to-the-Clouds/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/19/Debezium-Operator-Takes-off-to-the-Clouds/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/19/Debezium-Operator-Takes-off-to-the-Clouds/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium signaling and notifications - Part 3: JMX channel</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Welcome to the third installment of our series on Debezium Signaling and Notifications. In this article, we continue our exploration of Debezium signaling and notifications. In particular, we will delve into how to enable and manage these features using the JMX channel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;We will also explore how to send signals and get notifications through the REST API leveraging Jolokia.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/05/Debezium-JMX-signaling-and-notifications/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 10:11:11 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/05/Debezium-JMX-signaling-and-notifications/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/05/Debezium-JMX-signaling-and-notifications/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.0.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the summer months wind down and we enter autumn with cooler temperatures, the team has diligently prepared the next major milestone of Debezium. It&amp;#8217;s my pleasure to announce the immediate release of the next minor version, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.4.0.Final&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the team begins the journey toward the next development iteration, let&amp;#8217;s take a moment and review all the new features, changes, and improvements that are included in Debezium 2.4, which includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20and%20fixVersion%20%20in%20(2.4.0.Alpha1%2C%202.4.0.Alpha2%2C%202.4.0.Beta1%2C%202.4.0.Beta2%2C%202.4.0.CR1%2C%202.4.0.Final)&quot;&gt;231 issues&lt;/a&gt; resolved by 68 unique contributors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/03/debezium-2-4-final-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/03/debezium-2-4-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/10/03/debezium-2-4-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Online machine learning with the data streams from the database</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/05/02/tensorflow-mnist-classification/&quot;&gt;the previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, we have shown how to leverage Debezium to train neural-network model with the existing data from the database and use this pre-trained model to classify images newly stored into the database. In this blog post, we will move it one step further - we will use Debezium to create multiple data streams from the database and use one of the streams for continuous learning and to improve our model, and the second one for making predictions on the data. When the model is constantly improved or adjusted to recent data samples, this approach is known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Online_machine_learning&quot;&gt;online machine learning&lt;/a&gt;. Online learning is only suitable for some use cases, and implementing an online variant of a given algorithm may be challenging or even impossible. However, in situations where online learning is possible, it becomes a very powerful tool as it allows one to react to the changes in the data in real-time and avoids the need to re-train and re-deploy new models, thus saving the hardware and operational costs. As the streams of data become more and more common, e.g. with the advent of IoT, we can expect online learning to become more and more popular. It&amp;#8217;s usually a perfect fit for analyzing streaming data in use cases where it&amp;#8217;s possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/23/flink-spark-online-learning/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/23/flink-spark-online-learning/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/23/flink-spark-online-learning/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.0.CR1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the summer concludes for us in the north and we await the autumn colors, the team has been busy preparing for the next major release of Debezium 2.4. It&amp;#8217;s my pleasure to announce today that we are nearly there with the release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.4.0.CR1&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The focus for this release is primarily on stability; however, we do have a few new last minute addititons that we should highlight, so let&amp;#8217;s dive right in, shall we?!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;!- more -&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;breaking_changes&quot;&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The community led Vitess connector was retrying only a subset of errors by default. This behavior has been changed and now only explicitly defined errors are not retried. For more details, please see &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com&quot;&gt;DBZ-6944&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;new_features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;mongodb_parallel_incremental_snapshots&quot;&gt;MongoDB parallel incremental snapshots&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the introduction of incremental snapshots back in Debezium 1.x, the process to incremental snapshot existing data while concurrently capturing changes from a database transaction has been a single-threaded activity. It&amp;#8217;s not uncommon when adding new features to focus on the basics and build upon that foundation, which is precisely what has happened with MongoDB.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In Debezium 2.4, we are taking the first steps to add parallel support to incremental snapshots with the MongoDB connector by reading multiple chunks in parallel. This should allow faster throughput at the cost of memory while the chunks are being collected, sorted, and deduplication occurs against the transaction log capture data set. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/xidui&quot;&gt;Yue Wang&lt;/a&gt; for starting this effort in &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6518&quot;&gt;DBZ-6518&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;#8217;s most definitely something we are looking to explore for the relational connectors in an upcoming Debezium release.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;postgresql_16_support&quot;&gt;PostgreSQL 16 support&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL announced the immediate release for PostgreSQL 16 just over a week ago, and we&amp;#8217;re pleased to announce that Debezium 2.4 will support that release.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock note&quot;&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;fa icon-note&quot; title=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;PostgreSQL 16 introduces logical replication from standby servers; however, this feature has not yet been tested by Debezium and will be a feature introduced in a later build of Debezium. For now, logical replication remains only supported via the primary.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;google_spanner_gke_workload_identity_support&quot;&gt;Google Spanner GKE workload identity support&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Google Kubernetes Engine (GKE) supports identity workloads, allowing you to use a more secure authentication mechanism than the traditional JSON-based keys. In Debezium 2.4, when no JSON key is explicitly set, the Spanner connector will now automatically default to GKE workload identity authentication. Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laughingman7743&quot;&gt;laughingman7743&lt;/a&gt; for this effort as a part of &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6885&quot;&gt;DBZ-6885&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;other_fixes&quot;&gt;Other Fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ad-hoc blocking snaps trigger emits schema changes of all tables &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6828&quot;&gt;DBZ-6828&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When the start_scn corresponding to the existence of a transaction in V$TRANSACTION is 0, log mining starts from the oldest scn when the oracle connector is started for the first time &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6869&quot;&gt;DBZ-6869&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ensure that the connector can handle rebalance events robustly &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6870&quot;&gt;DBZ-6870&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;OpenLogReplicator confirmation can resend or omit events on restarts &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6895&quot;&gt;DBZ-6895&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;ExtractNewRecordState&amp;#8217;s schema cache is not updated with arrival of the ddl change event &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6901&quot;&gt;DBZ-6901&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Misleading Debezium error message when RDI port is not specified in application.properties &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6902&quot;&gt;DBZ-6902&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Generting protobuf files to target/generated-sources breaks build &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6903&quot;&gt;DBZ-6903&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Clean log printout in Redis Debezium Sink &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6908&quot;&gt;DBZ-6908&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Values being omitted from list of JSON object &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6910&quot;&gt;DBZ-6910&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;fix logger named &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6935&quot;&gt;DBZ-6935&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;MySql connector get NPE when snapshot.mode is set to never and signal data collection configured &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6937&quot;&gt;DBZ-6937&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sanity check / retry for redo logs does not work per Oracle RAC thread &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6938&quot;&gt;DBZ-6938&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Drop events has wrong table changes information &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6945&quot;&gt;DBZ-6945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Remove spaces from Signal and Notification MBean&amp;#8217;s ObjectName &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6957&quot;&gt;DBZ-6957&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Altogether, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%202.4.0.CR1%20ORDER%20BY%20component%20ASC&quot;&gt;20 issues&lt;/a&gt; were fixed for this release. A big thank you to all the contributors from the community who worked on this release: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BigGillyStyle&quot;&gt;Andy Pickler&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ani-sha&quot;&gt;Anisha Mohanty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brenoavm&quot;&gt;Breno Moreira&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Naros&quot;&gt;Chris Cranford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/harveyyue&quot;&gt;Harvey Yue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/indraraj&quot;&gt;Indra Shukla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jcechace&quot;&gt;Jakub Cechacek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jpechane&quot;&gt;Jiri Pechanec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mfvitale&quot;&gt;Mario Fiore Vitale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nancyxu123&quot;&gt;Nancy Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nirolevy&quot;&gt;Nir Levy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/obabec&quot;&gt;Ondrej Babec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rk3rn3r&quot;&gt;René Kerner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eizners&quot;&gt;Sergey Eizner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twthorn&quot;&gt;Thomas Thornton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/wuzhenhua01&quot;&gt;Wu Zhenhua&lt;/a&gt;, Zheng Wang, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laughingman7743&quot;&gt;laughingman7743&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tisonkun&quot;&gt;tison&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;outlook_and_whats_next&quot;&gt;Outlook and What&amp;#8217;s next?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re now at the junction where we begin to set our vision on Debezium 2.5 and what lies ahead. We recently held our first Community Meeting and discussed a number of our 2.5 roadmap ideas, some of which include:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Parallel incremental snapshots for relational connectors.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Improved MongoDB support for BSONDocument exceeding 16MB.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Db2 support on z/OS and iSeries platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Batch support in the JDBC sink connector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Parallelization of tasks and other Debezium Engine internals.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Preview of MariaDB and Oracle 23 support&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;For more details, please check out our &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/roadmap&quot;&gt;road map&lt;/a&gt; for all upcoming details around Debezium 2.5 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, Debezium will be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.confluent.io/events/current/&quot;&gt;Current 2023&lt;/a&gt; next week. If you are attending, be sure to stop by the Ask-The-Experts session on Wednesday at 2:30PM to catch a sesssion on Debezium and Kafka. Additionally, be sure to check out the sponsored session on Wednesday at 4:30PM to find out just how easy it is to deploy data pipelines from the edge to the cloud using open-source projects such as Debezium, Strimzi, Apicurio, and Kubernetes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any questions, suggestions, or feedback, please reach out to us on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/debezium&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.zulipchat.com/login/#narrow/stream/302529-users&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt;. We always enjoy hearing what you have to share. Until next time, be safe.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/22/debezium-2-4-cr1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/22/debezium-2-4-cr1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/22/debezium-2-4-cr1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.0.Beta2 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;It has been nearly two weeks since our last preview release of the Debezium 2.4 series, and I am thrilled to announcement the next installation of that series, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.4.0.Beta2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While typically beta releases focus on stability and bugs, this release includes quite a number of noteworthy improves and new features including a new ingestion method for Oracle using OpenLogReplicator, a new single message transform to handle timezone conversions, custom authentication support for MongoDB, configurable order for the MongoDB aggregation pipeline, and lastly support for MongoDB 7.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take a few moments and dive into all these new features, improvements, and changes in more detail.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/13/debezium-2-4-beta2-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/13/debezium-2-4-beta2-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/13/debezium-2-4-beta2-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Enable pass-through of additional properties in Debezium UI</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium UI team continues to add support for more features, allowing users to configure connectors more easily. In this article, we&amp;#8217;ll describe and demonstrate how to provide the additional properties for configuration that the UI does not expose by default. Read further for more information!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/10/Debezium-UI-connectors-custom-property/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/10/Debezium-UI-connectors-custom-property/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/10/Debezium-UI-connectors-custom-property/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.3.3.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is my pleasure to announce the immediate release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.3.3.Final&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release includes several bug fixes to address regressions, stability, documentation updates. If you are currently looking to upgrade to the Debezium 2.3.x release stream, we highly recommend you consider using this release. Let&amp;#8217;s take a quick look into the regressions and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/05/debezium-2-3-3-final-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/05/debezium-2-3-3-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/09/05/debezium-2-3-3-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.0.Beta1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While development remains steadfast as we continue forward on Debezium 2.4, I am thrilled to announce the immediate availability of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.4.0.Beta1&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;While this release focuses on stability and bug fixes, there are several new noteworthy features including TimescaleDB support, JMX notifications using JSON payloads, multiple improvements to the Oracle connector&amp;#8217;s metrics and embedded Infinispan buffer implementation, SQL Server heartbeats, Vitess shardless strategy, JDBC sink with SQL Server identity-based inserts, and much more. Let&amp;#8217;s dive into each of thees new features and others in more detail.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/29/debezium-2-4-beta1-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/29/debezium-2-4-beta1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/29/debezium-2-4-beta1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.4.0.Alpha2 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Despite summer being well underway, Debezium contributors remain hard at work, and it&amp;#8217;s my pleasure to announce the next preview release of Debezium 2.4 series, &lt;strong&gt;2.4.0.Alpha2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This preview release includes a mix of improvements, bug fixes, and new features that are available for the Debezium community to test and offer feedback. Some highlights from this release include ad-hoc blocking snapshots, source-to-sink column name propagation, support for alternative MySQL drivers, and all Cassandra connectors with Debezium Server. Let&amp;#8217;s take a few moments and dive into these and others.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;!- more --&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#breaking-changes&quot;&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#new-features&quot;&gt;New features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#other-changes&quot;&gt;Other changes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#whats-next&quot;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;breaking-changes&quot;&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;debezium_server_and_cassandra_connectors&quot;&gt;Debezium Server and Cassandra connectors&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;For Cassandra connector users who may have been using Debezium Server or who may have wanted to use Debezium Server, we previously only shipped Cassandra 4 with the Debezium Server distribution. With Debezium 2.4, we now include all three Cassandra connector variants with the distribution, meaning that Cassandra 3 and DSE can now be used directly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, for this to work, a new environment variable &lt;code&gt;EXTRA_CONNECTOR&lt;/code&gt; was introduced to specify specifically which Cassandra connector variant should be used by Debezium Server. This means that if you were using Cassandra 4 with Debezium Server, you must include this environment variable when upgrading to have the same configuration continue to work as it did in prior versions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This new environment variable should be set to &lt;code&gt;dse&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cassandra-3&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;cassandra-4&lt;/code&gt; depending on the Cassandra version you intend to use for your Debezium Server source connector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;mysql_bigint_precision_changed&quot;&gt;MySQL BIGINT precision changed&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium for MySQL connector was not properly setting the precision for &lt;code&gt;BIGINT&lt;/code&gt; data types when configuring the connector with &lt;code&gt;bigint.unsigned.handling.mode&lt;/code&gt; as &lt;code&gt;precise&lt;/code&gt;. Unfortunately, this led to a situation where the schema for such fields did not include the correct precision value.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium 2.4 includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6714&quot;&gt;DBZ-6714&lt;/a&gt;, which provides a fix to address the incorrect precision for such fields. This can lead to schema incompatibilities when using schema registry, so you may need to adjust your compatibility settings or take other actions if you need to use strict compatibility rules.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;oracle_snapshot_and_query_fetch_sizes_increased&quot;&gt;Oracle snapshot and query fetch sizes increased&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium 2.4 introduces a change in the default values for the &lt;code&gt;snapshot.fetch.size&lt;/code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;query.fetch.size&lt;/code&gt; Oracle connector configuration properties. Previously, these properties used a default of &lt;code&gt;2000&lt;/code&gt;; however, thanks to a community contributor, it was identified that these values may likely be too low for production use.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;With this release, the Oracle connector will now use a default of &lt;code&gt;10000&lt;/code&gt; for both properties, which should have a positive improvement on throughput for most users who were not explicitly setting these values. If you were previously using custom values for these settings in your connector configurations, then you will not see a change in your existing behavior. Only users who previously were not explicitly setting these values will notice that the new defaults will be used.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock note&quot;&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;fa icon-note&quot; title=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;These configuration properties are meant to act as tuning knobs, as a specific configuration for one JDBC environment may not work as well in a different environment. While we believe this change will have no negative impact, if you do notice a drop in performance, you can add these properties to your connector configuration setting them to their previous defaults of &lt;code&gt;2000&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;vitess_incorrectly_mapped_bin_columns&quot;&gt;Vitess incorrectly mapped &lt;code&gt;_bin&lt;/code&gt; columns&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;For collations that end with the &lt;code&gt;_bin&lt;/code&gt; designator, Vitess maps these to a data type of &lt;code&gt;VARBINARY&lt;/code&gt;. As a result, the Vitess connector was inferring that these columns should be emitted as binary data; however, for character-based columns that used such collations, this was incorrect.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium 2.4 will now properly emit character-based columns that are collated with a &lt;code&gt;_bin&lt;/code&gt; designator as string-based data rather than binary data. This means that if you are using schema registry, you may observe somee schema incompatibilities and you may need to adjust your compatibility settings or take other actions to mitigate this change.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;new-features&quot;&gt;New Features&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;ad_hoc_blocking_snapshots&quot;&gt;Ad-hoc blocking snapshots&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Incremental snapshots were first introduced nearly two years ago in Debezium 1.6 and has remained quite popular in the community to deal with a variety of re-snapshot use cases. However, there are some use cases where the intertwined nature of read events with create, updates, and deletes may be less than ideal or even not supported by some consumer application. For those use cases, Debezium 2.4 introduces ad-hoc blocking snapshots.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;An ad-hoc blocking snapshot works in a similar way that ad-hoc incremental snapshots work; however, with one major difference. The snapshot is still triggered by sending a signal to Debezium; however when the signal is processed by the connector, the key difference is that streaming is put on hold while the snapshot process runs. This means you won&amp;#8217;t be receiving a series of read events interwoven with create, update, or delete events. This also means that we&amp;#8217;ll be processing the snapshot in a similar way to traditional snapshots, so the throughput should generally be higher than incremental snapshots.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock important&quot;&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;fa icon-important&quot; title=&quot;Important&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Be aware that ad-hoc blocking snapshots puts the reading of the transaction logs on hold while the snapshot is performed. This means the same requirements that a traditional snapshot has on transaction log availability also applies when using this type of ad-hoc snapshot mode. When streaming resumes, if a transaction log that is needed has since been removed, the connector will raise an error and stop.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The signal to initiate an ad-hoc blocking snapshot is very similar to its ad-hoc incremental snapshot counterpart. The following signal below shows the payload to snapshot a specific table with a condition, but this uses the new blocking snapshot rather than the incremental snapshot:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;CodeRay highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code data-lang=&quot;json&quot;&gt;{ &lt;span class=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;execute-snapshot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: { &lt;span class=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;data-collections&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: [&lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;public.my_table&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;], &lt;span class=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;BLOCKING&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;i class=&quot;conum&quot; data-value=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;(1)&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;key&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;additional-condition&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;: &lt;span class=&quot;string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;content&quot;&gt;last_update_date &amp;gt;= '2023-01-01'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;delimiter&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; } }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;colist arabic&quot;&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;conum&quot; data-value=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/td&gt; &lt;td&gt;The use of &lt;code&gt;BLOCKING&lt;/code&gt; rather than &lt;code&gt;INCREMENTAL&lt;/code&gt; differentiates the two ad-hoc snapshot modes.&lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;source_to_sink_column_name_propagation&quot;&gt;Source-to-sink column name propagation&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Normally column names map directly to field names and vice versa when consumed by sink connectors such as a JDBC connector. However, there are situations where the serialization technology, such as Avro, has very specific rules about field naming conventions. When a column&amp;#8217;s name in a database table conflicts with the serialization rule&amp;#8217;s naming conventions, Debezium will rename the field in the event so that it adheres to the serialization&amp;#8217;s rules. This often means that a field will be prepended with underscores or invalid characters replaced with underscores.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This can create problems for certain types of sinks, such as a JDBC sink connector, because the sink cannot easily deduce the original column name for the destination table nor can it adequately map between the event&amp;#8217;s field name and a column name if they differ. This typically means users must use transformation chains on the sink side in order to reconstruct the event&amp;#8217;s fields with namings that represent the source.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Debezium 2.4 introduces a way to minimize and potentially avoid that entirely by propagating the original column name as a field schema parameter, much in the same way that we do for data types, precision, scale, and length. The schema parameter &lt;code&gt;__debezium.source.column.name&lt;/code&gt; now includes the original column name when column or data type propagation is enabled.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;admonitionblock tip&quot;&gt; &lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;icon&quot;&gt; &lt;i class=&quot;fa icon-tip&quot; title=&quot;Tip&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;td class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium JDBC sink connector already works with column and data type propagation, allowing for the sink connector to more accurately deduce column types, length, precision, and scale.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;With this new feature, the JDBC sink connector will automatically use the column name from this argument when it is provided to guarantee that the destination table will be created with the same column names as the source, even when using Avro or similar. This means no transformations are needed when using the Debezium JDBC sink connector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/td&gt; &lt;/tr&gt; &lt;/table&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect2&quot;&gt; &lt;h3 id=&quot;alternative_mysql_jdbc_drivers&quot;&gt;Alternative MySQL JDBC drivers&lt;/h3&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In order to use IAM authentication on AWS, a special MySQL driver is required to provide that type of functionality. With Debezium 2.4, you can now provide a reference to this specific driver and the connector will use that driver instead of the default driver shipped with the connector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As an example, to connect using IAM authentication on AWS, the following configuration is needed:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;listingblock&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;content&quot;&gt; &lt;pre class=&quot;CodeRay highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code data-lang=&quot;text&quot;&gt;database.jdbc.driver=software.aws.rds.jdbc.mysql.Driver database.jdbc.protocol=jdbc:mysql:aws&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;database.jdbc.driver&lt;/code&gt; specifies the driver that should be loaded by the connector and used to communicate with the MySQL database. The &lt;code&gt;database.jdbc.protocol&lt;/code&gt; is a supplemental configuration property that may not be required in all contexts. It defaults to &lt;code&gt;jdbc:mysql&lt;/code&gt; but since AWS requires &lt;code&gt;jdbc:mysql:aws&lt;/code&gt;, this allows you to specify this derivative within the configuration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ve love to hear feedback and whether something like this might be useful for other scenarios.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;other-changes&quot;&gt;Other fixes&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition, there were quite a number of stability and bug fixes that made it into this release. These include the following:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Switch tracing to OpenTelemetry &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-2862&quot;&gt;DBZ-2862&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Connector drop down causes a scroll bar &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-5421&quot;&gt;DBZ-5421&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Provide outline for drawer component showing connector details &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-5831&quot;&gt;DBZ-5831&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Modify scroll for the running connector component &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-5832&quot;&gt;DBZ-5832&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Connector restart regression &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6213&quot;&gt;DBZ-6213&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Highlight information about how to configure the schema history topic to store data only for intended tables &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6219&quot;&gt;DBZ-6219&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Document Optimal MongoDB Oplog Config for Resiliency &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6455&quot;&gt;DBZ-6455&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;JDBC Schema History: When the table name is passed as dbName.tableName, the connector does not start &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6484&quot;&gt;DBZ-6484&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Update the Edit connector UI to incorporate the feedback received from team in demo &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6514&quot;&gt;DBZ-6514&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support blocking ad-hoc snapshots &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6566&quot;&gt;DBZ-6566&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add new parameters to RabbitMQ consumer &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6581&quot;&gt;DBZ-6581&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Document read preference changes in 2.4 &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6591&quot;&gt;DBZ-6591&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle DDL parser does not properly detect end of statement when comments obfuscate the semicolon &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6599&quot;&gt;DBZ-6599&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Received an unexpected message type that does not have an 'after' Debezium block &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6637&quot;&gt;DBZ-6637&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;When Debezium Mongodb connector encounter authentication or under privilege errors, the connection between debezium and mongodb keeps going up. &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6643&quot;&gt;DBZ-6643&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Log appropriate error when JDBC connector receive SchemaChange record &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6655&quot;&gt;DBZ-6655&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Send tombstone events when partition queries are finished &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6658&quot;&gt;DBZ-6658&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Snapshot will not capture data when signal.data.collection is present without table.include.list &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6669&quot;&gt;DBZ-6669&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Retriable operations are retried infinitely since error handlers are not reused &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6670&quot;&gt;DBZ-6670&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle DDL parser does not support column visibility on ALTER TABLE &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6677&quot;&gt;DBZ-6677&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Propagate source column name and allow sink to use it &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6684&quot;&gt;DBZ-6684&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Partition duplication after rebalances with single leader task &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6685&quot;&gt;DBZ-6685&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;JDBC Sink Connector Fails on Loading Flat Data Containing Struct Type Fields from Kafka &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6686&quot;&gt;DBZ-6686&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;SQLSyntaxErrorException using Debezium JDBC Sink connector &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6687&quot;&gt;DBZ-6687&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Should use topic.prefix rather than connector.server.name in MBean namings &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6690&quot;&gt;DBZ-6690&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;CDC - Debezium x RabbitMQ - Debezium Server crashes when an UPDATE/DELETE on source database (PostgreSQL) &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6691&quot;&gt;DBZ-6691&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Missing operationTime field on ping command when executed against Atlas &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6700&quot;&gt;DBZ-6700&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;MongoDB SRV protocol not working in Debezium Server &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6701&quot;&gt;DBZ-6701&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Disable jdk-outreach-workflow.yml in forked personal repo &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6702&quot;&gt;DBZ-6702&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Custom properties step not working correctly in validation of the properties added by user &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6711&quot;&gt;DBZ-6711&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add tzdata-java to UI installation Dockerfile &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6713&quot;&gt;DBZ-6713&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Refactor EmbeddedEngine::run method &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6715&quot;&gt;DBZ-6715&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle fails to process a DROP USER &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6716&quot;&gt;DBZ-6716&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support alternative JDBC drivers in MySQL connector &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6727&quot;&gt;DBZ-6727&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle LogMiner mining distance calculation should be skipped when upper bounds is not within distance &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6733&quot;&gt;DBZ-6733&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add STOPPED and RESTARTING connector states to testing library &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6734&quot;&gt;DBZ-6734&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;MariaDB: Unparseable DDL statement (ALTER TABLE IF EXISTS) &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6736&quot;&gt;DBZ-6736&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Update Quarkus to 3.2.3.Final &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6740&quot;&gt;DBZ-6740&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Decouple Debezium Server and Extension Quarkus versions &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6744&quot;&gt;DBZ-6744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;SingleProcessor remove redundant filter logic &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6745&quot;&gt;DBZ-6745&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;MySQL dialect does not properly recognize non-default value longblob types due to typo &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6753&quot;&gt;DBZ-6753&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add a new parameter for selecting the db index when using Redis Storage &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6759&quot;&gt;DBZ-6759&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Postgres tests for toasted byte array and toasted date array fail with decoderbufs plugin &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6767&quot;&gt;DBZ-6767&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Table schemas should be updated for each shard individually &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6775&quot;&gt;DBZ-6775&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Notifications and signals leaks between MBean instances when using JMX channels &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6777&quot;&gt;DBZ-6777&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle XML column types are not properly resolved when adding XMLTYPE column during streaming &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6782&quot;&gt;DBZ-6782&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Bump the MySQL binlog client version to 0.28.1 which includes significant GTID event performance improvements &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6783&quot;&gt;DBZ-6783&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Add new Redis Sink connector parameter description to the documentation &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6784&quot;&gt;DBZ-6784&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Upgrade Kafka to 3.5.1 &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/browse/DBZ-6785&quot;&gt;DBZ-6785&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Altogether, &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%202.4.0.Alpha2%20ORDER%20BY%20component%20ASC&quot;&gt;62 issues&lt;/a&gt; were fixed for this release. A big thank you to all the contributors from the community who worked on this release: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/roldanbob&quot;&gt;Bob Roldan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/TyrantLucifer&quot;&gt;Chao Tian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Naros&quot;&gt;Chris Cranford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/C0urante&quot;&gt;Chris Egerton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vidourem&quot;&gt;David Remy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/faihofu&quot;&gt;Fai Ho Fu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/gurpiarbassi&quot;&gt;Gurps Bassi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/harveyyue&quot;&gt;Harvey Yue&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/indraraj&quot;&gt;Indra Shukla&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jcechace&quot;&gt;Jakub Cechacek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jpechane&quot;&gt;Jiri Pechanec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/joschi&quot;&gt;Jochen Schalanda&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mfvitale&quot;&gt;Mario Fiore Vitale&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mfortunat&quot;&gt;Massimo Fortunat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nancyxu123&quot;&gt;Nancy Xu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/benesch&quot;&gt;Nikhil Benesch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/paul-cheung&quot;&gt;Paul Cheung&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/roldanbob&quot;&gt;Robert Roldan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ironakj&quot;&gt;Ronak Jain&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ryanvanhuuksloot&quot;&gt;Ryan van Huuksloot&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/eizners&quot;&gt;Sergey Eizner&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/twthorn&quot;&gt;Thomas Thornton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vjuranek&quot;&gt;Vojtech Juranek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/j2gg0s&quot;&gt;Yanjie Wang&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Ychopada&quot;&gt;Yashashree Chopada&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/vidourem&quot;&gt;david remy&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ibnubay&quot;&gt;ibnubay&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sect1&quot;&gt; &lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s next?&lt;/h2&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;sectionbody&quot;&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium 2.4 series is already packed with lots of new features, and we&amp;#8217;re only scratching the surface. We have more in-store, including the new Oracle OpenLogReplicator adapter coming with Debezium 2.4 Alpha3 next week. After that, we&amp;#8217;ll begin to wind down the development and shift our focus in the beta and release candidate cycle, targeting the end of September for a Debezium 2.4 final release.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t forget about the Debezium Community Event, which I shared with you on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/debezium&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any ideas or suggestions, I&amp;#8217;d love your feedback. We will be making an announcement in the next two weeks about the date/time and agenda.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Additionally, if you&amp;#8217;re going to Current 2023 this year in San Jose, I&amp;#8217;d love to meet up and discuss your experiences with Debezium. I&amp;#8217;ll be there doing a talk on event-driven design with Debezium and Apicurio with my good friends Hans-Peter Grahsl and Carles Arnal. If you&amp;#8217;re interested in more details, feel free to drop me a line in chat, on the mailing list or directly via email.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As always, if you have any ideas or suggestions, you can also get in touch with us on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/g/debezium&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; or our &lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.zulipchat.com/login/#narrow/stream/302529-users&quot;&gt;chat&lt;/a&gt;. Until next time, don&amp;#8217;t be a stranger and stay cool out there!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/09/debezium-2-4-alpha2-released/&quot;&gt;Read more...&lt;/a&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/09/debezium-2-4-alpha2-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/08/09/debezium-2-4-alpha2-released/</guid> </item> </channel> </rss>