<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"> <channel> <title></title> <description>Debezium is an open source distributed platform for change data capture. Start it up, point it at your databases, and your apps can start responding to all of the inserts, updates, and deletes that other apps commit to your databases. Debezium is durable and fast, so your apps can respond quickly and never miss an event, even when things go wrong.</description> <sy:updatePeriod>daily</sy:updatePeriod> <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency> <link>https://debezium.io</link> <atom:link href="https://debezium.io/blog.atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/> <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:11:11 +0000</lastBuildDate> <item> <title>Hello Debezium Team!</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hi everyone, my name is Mario Fiore Vitale and I recently joined Red Hat and the Debezium team.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am a very curious person that follows a continuous learning approach, I like to keep growing my skills. I care about code quality and readability.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I have about 9+ years of experience and have worked for consultancy, startup, and enterprise product companies in different sectors. In my previously experience I had the chance to work on architecture re-design project to split a monolith into a microservices application. During this experience I gained experience with different technologies such as Kafka, Elasticsearch, Redis, Kubernetes, VictoriaMetrics, Spring Framework, and a bit of Cassandra.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Why Am I here?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 10:11:11 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/03/09/hello-debezium/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/03/09/hello-debezium/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.2.0.Alpha3 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today, I am pleased to announce the third alpha release in the 2.2 release stream, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.2.0.Alpha3&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release includes a plethora of bug fixes, improvements, breaking changes, and a number of new features including, but not limited to, optional parallel snapshots, server-side MongoDB change stream filtering, surrogate keys for incremental snapshots, a new Cassandra connector for Cassandra Enterprise, much more.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s take moment and dive into some of these new features, improvements, and breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/03/08/debezium-2-2-alpha3-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/03/08/debezium-2-2-alpha3-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.2.0.Alpha2 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today, I am pleased to announce the second alpha release in the 2.2 release stream, Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.2.0.Alpha2&lt;/strong&gt;. This release includes a plethora of bug fixes, improvements, breaking changes, and a number of new features including, but not limited to, a new &lt;code&gt;ExtractRecordChanges&lt;/code&gt; single message transformation, a Reactive-based implementation of the Debezium Outbox extension for Quarkus, a Debezium Storage module for Apache RocketMQ, and much more. Let&amp;#8217;s take moment and dive into these new features, improvements, and breaking changes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/02/16/debezium-2-2-alpha2-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/02/16/debezium-2-2-alpha2-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>DDD Aggregates via CDC-CQRS Pipeline using Kafka &amp; Debezium</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this post, we are going to talk about a CDC-CQRS pipeline between a normalized relational database, MySQL, as the command database and a de-normalized NoSQL database, MongoDB, as the query database resulting in the creation of DDD Aggregates via Debezium &amp;amp; Kafka-Streams.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/02/04/ddd-aggregates-via-cdc-cqrs-pipeline-using-kafka-and-debezium/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/02/04/ddd-aggregates-via-cdc-cqrs-pipeline-using-kafka-and-debezium/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.1.2.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium release cadence is in full swing as I&amp;#8217;m excited to announce Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.1.2.Final&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release focuses primarily on bug fixes and stability; and it is the recommended update for all users from earlier versions. This release contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project+%3D+DBZ+AND+fixVersion+%3D+2.1.2.Final&quot;&gt;28 resolved issues&lt;/a&gt;, so let&amp;#8217;s take a moment and discuss a critical breaking change.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/26/debezium-2-1-2-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/26/debezium-2-1-2-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>We Are Hiring (Saga continues)</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In November last year, we &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2022/11/15/filling-the-ranks/&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; we were looking for reinforcements for the team. And I have two pieces of news for you today: a good one and an even better one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/24/we-are-hiring-2/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/24/we-are-hiring-2/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.2.0.Alpha1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s my pleasure to announce not only the first release of the Debezium 2.2 series, but also the first release of Debezium in 2023, &lt;strong&gt;2.2.0.Alpha&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium 2.2.0.Alpha1 release includes some breaking changes, a number of bug fixes, and some noteworthy improvements and features, including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[Breaking Change] - &lt;code&gt;ZonedTimestamp&lt;/code&gt; values will no longer truncate fractional seconds.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[New] - Support ingesting changes from an Oracle logical stand-by database&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[New] - Support Amazon S3 buckets using the Debezium Storage API&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[New] - Support retrying database connections during connector start-up&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;[New] - Debezium Server sink connector support for Apache RocketMQ and Infinispan&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/19/debezium-2-2-alpha1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/19/debezium-2-2-alpha1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Change Data Capture with QuestDB and Debezium</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This tutorial was originally published by &lt;a href=&quot;https://questdb.io/&quot;&gt;QuestDB&lt;/a&gt;, where guest contributor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://yitaek.medium.com/&quot;&gt;Yitaek Hwang&lt;/a&gt;, shows us how to stream data into QuestDB with change data capture via Debezium and Kafka Connect.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/06/change-data-capture-with-questdb-and-debezium/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2023/01/06/change-data-capture-with-questdb-and-debezium/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.1.0.Final/Debezium 2.1.1.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today it&amp;#8217;s my great pleasure to announce the availability of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.1.0.Final&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;You might recently noticed that Debezium went a bit silent for the last few weeks. No, we are not going away. In fact the elves in Google worked furiously to bring you a present under a Christmas tree - Debezium Spanner connector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/12/22/debezium-2-1-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/12/22/debezium-2-1-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Filling the Ranks</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;As you are probably well aware, Gunnar Morling has stepped down from his position as Debezium project lead and is now pursuing new exciting adventures. It is sad, but every cloud has a silver lining!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;What can it be? We (the Debezium team and Red Hat) are hiring! Are you a community contributor? Do you have any pull requests under your belt? Are you a happy Debezium user and eager to do more, or are you a seasoned Java developer looking for work in an exciting and inclusive open-source environment?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/11/15/filling-the-ranks/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/11/15/filling-the-ranks/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.1.0.Alpha1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s my pleasure to announce the first release of the Debezium 2.1 series, &lt;strong&gt;2.1.0.Alpha1&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Debezium 2.1.0.Alpha1 release includes quite a number of bug fixes but also some noteworthy improvements and new features including but not limited to:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;ulist&quot;&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Support for PostgreSQL 15&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Single Message Transformation (SMT) predicate support in Debezium engine&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Capturing TRUNCATE as change event in MySQL table topics&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;Oracle LogMiner performance improvements&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;p&gt;New Redis-based storage module&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/11/10/debezium-2-1-alpha1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/11/10/debezium-2-1-alpha1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium Evolving</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some time in early 2017, I got a meeting invite from Debezium&amp;#8217;s founder, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rhauch&quot;&gt;Randall Hauch&lt;/a&gt;. He was about to begin a new chapter in his professional career and was looking for someone to take over as the project lead for Debezium. So we hopped on a call to talk things through, and I was immediately sold on the concept of change data capture, its large number of potential use cases and applications, and the idea of making this available to the community as open-source. After some short consideration I decided to take up this opportunity, and without a doubt this has been one of the best decisions I&amp;#8217;ve ever made in my job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/26/debezium-evolving/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/26/debezium-evolving/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 1.9.7.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m excited to announce the release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;1.9.7.Final&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release focuses on bug fixes and stability; and is the recommended update for all users from earlier versions. This release contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project+%3D+DBZ+AND+fixVersion+%3D+1.9.7.Final&quot;&gt;22 resolved issues&lt;/a&gt; overall.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/26/debezium-1-9-7-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/26/debezium-1-9-7-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debugging flaky tests</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;When developing the tests for your project, sooner or later you will probably get into the situation when some of the tests fail randomly. These tests, also known as flaky tests, are very unpleasant as you never know if the failure was random or there is a regression in your code. In the worst case you just ignore these tests because you know they are flaky. Most of the testing frameworks even have a dedicated annotation or other means to express that the test is flaky and if it fails, the failure should be ignored. The value of such a test is very questionable. The best thing you can do with such a test is of course to fix it so that it doesn&amp;#8217;t fail randomly. That&amp;#8217;s easy to say, but harder to do. The hardest part is usually to make the test fail in your development environment so that you can debug it and understand why it fails and what is the root cause of the failure. In this blog post I&amp;#8217;ll try to show a few techniques which may help you to simulate random test failures on you local machine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/20/flaky-tests/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/20/flaky-tests/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.0.0.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Today it&amp;#8217;s my great pleasure to announce the availability of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.0.0.Final&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since our 1.0 release in December 2019, the community has worked vigorously to build a comprehensive open-source low-latency platform for change data capture (CDC). Over the past three years, we have extended Debezium&amp;#8217;s portfolio to include a stable connector for Oracle, a community led connector for Vitess, the introduction of incremental snapshots, multi-partition support, and so much more. With the help of our active community of contributors and committers, Debezium is the de facto leader in the CDC space, deployed to production within lots of organizations from across multiple industries, using hundreds of connectors to stream data changes out of thousands of database platforms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;The 2.0 release marks a new milestone for Debezium, one that we are proud to share with each of you.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/17/debezium-2-0-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/17/debezium-2-0-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.0.0.CR1 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce the release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.0.0.CR1&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release contains breaking changes, stability fixes, and bug fixes, all to inch us closer to 2.0.0.Final. Overall, this release contains a total of &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%202.0.0.CR1%20ORDER%20BY%20component%20ASC&quot;&gt;53 issues&lt;/a&gt; that were fixed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/10/debezium-2.0-cr1-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/10/debezium-2.0-cr1-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium for Oracle - Part 2: Running the connector</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This post is part of a 3-part series to explore using Debezium to ingest changes from an Oracle database using Oracle LogMiner. In case you missed it, the first part of this series is &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2022/09/30/debezium-oracle-series-part-1/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;In this second installment, we will build on what we did in part one by deploying the Oracle connector using Zookeeper, Kafka, and Kafka Connect. We are going to discuss a variety of configuration options for the connector and why they&amp;#8217;re essential. And finally, we&amp;#8217;re going to see the connector in action!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/06/debezium-oracle-series-part-2/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/10/06/debezium-oracle-series-part-2/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium for Oracle - Part 1: Installation and Setup</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This post is part of a 3-part series to explore using Debezium to ingest changes from an Oracle database using Oracle LogMiner. Throughout the series, we&amp;#8217;ll examine all the steps to setting up a proof of concept (POC) deployment for Debezium for Oracle. We will discuss setup and configurations as well as the nuances of multi-tenancy. We will also dive into any known pitfalls and concerns you may need to know and how to debug specific problems. And finally, we&amp;#8217;ll talk about performance and monitoring to maintain a healthy connector deployment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;Throughout this exercise, we hope that this will show you just how simple it is to deploy Debezium for Oracle. This installation and setup portion of the series may seem quite complicated, but many of these steps likely already exist in a pre-existing environment. We will dive into each step, explaining it is essential should you use a container image deployment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/30/debezium-oracle-series-part-1/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/30/debezium-oracle-series-part-1/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 1.9.6.Final Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m excited to announce the release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;1.9.6.Final&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release focuses on bug fixes and stability; and is the recommended update for all users from earlier versions. This release contains &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project+%3D+DBZ+AND+fixVersion+%3D+1.9.6.Final&quot;&gt;78 resolved issues&lt;/a&gt; overall.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/26/debezium-1-9-6-final-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/26/debezium-1-9-6-final-released/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Debezium 2.0.0.Beta2 Released</title> <description>&lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am excited to announce the release of Debezium &lt;strong&gt;2.0.0.Beta2&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;div class=&quot;paragraph&quot;&gt; &lt;p&gt;This release contains several breaking changes, stability fixes, and bug fixes, all to inch us closer to 2.0.0.Final. Overall, this release contains a total of &lt;a href=&quot;https://issues.redhat.com/issues/?jql=project%20%3D%20DBZ%20AND%20fixVersion%20%3D%202.0.0.Beta2%20ORDER%20BY%20component%20ASC&quot;&gt;107 issues&lt;/a&gt; that were fixed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description> <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate> <link>https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/16/debezium-2.0-beta2-released/</link> <guid isPermaLink="true">https://debezium.io/blog/2022/09/16/debezium-2.0-beta2-released/</guid> </item> </channel> </rss>